(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T04:45:57.446213",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
歌が、好きなままでいれてよかった。
I'm so glad I could keep loving to sing.
春の風に吹かれて
Blown by the spring breeze,
わたげ ふわり 横切っていく
fluffy tufts drift softly across.
どこまで行くのかな 僕も辿り着けるかな
Where will it go? Can I reach there too?
ふっと歩みを止めて 振り返って見る自分は
Stopping for a moment and looking back,
どんな風に映ってる？ 純白のハナミズキ揺れる
how do I look? Pure white dogwoods sway.
ふっと歩みを止めて 振り返って
Stopping for a moment and turning around,
見る自分は どんな風に
how does the self I see
映ってる？ 純白のハナミズキ
reflect? Pure white dogwoods
揺れる
are swaying.
ちょっと、君に会いたい
I just want to see you,
1分1秒、分け合いたい
share every minute and second,
優しいあの声 今なんだか聴きたくなったよ
and somehow I wanted to hear that gentle voice right now.
なんだか聴きたくなったよ また会いたいよ
Somehow I wanted to hear it... I want to see you again.
夏の空は青くて 風鈴 花火 響き渡っていく
The summer sky is blue, wind chimes and fireworks echoing across.
どこまで届くのかな そっと口ずさむメロディー
Where will it reach? A melody hummed softly.
君は今何してる？ どんなこと考えてるの？
What are you doing now? What are you thinking about?
春の風に吹かれて
Blown by the spring breeze,
綿毛 ふわり 横切っていく
tufts of wool drift past.
どこまで行くのかな
I wonder how far I'll go,
僕もたどり着けるかな
and if I can make it too.
ふっと足を止めて 振り返って見る自分は
Humming a melody softly,
どんな風に映ってる? 純白のハナミズキ揺れる
pure white dogwood flowers sway.
ちょっと、君に会いたい 1分1秒、分け合いたい
I want to see you just a little bit,
優しいあの声今なんか聞きたくなったよ
sharing every single minute and second.
夏の空は青くて
The summer sky is blue,
風鈴 花火 鳴り響いていく
with wind chimes and fireworks echoing.
どこまで届くかな
I wonder how far it reaches,
そっと口ずさむメロディー
humming a melody to myself.
君は今何してる?
What are you doing now?
どんなこと考えてるの?
What kind of things are you thinking about?
気づくとまた想ってる 鮮緑のハナミズキ揺れる
Before I know it, I'm thinking of you again,
やっぱ、君に会いたい 1分1秒、分け合いたい
as the vivid green dogwood flowers sway.
君のこと 何でもいいの 聞かせてほしい
I really want to see you, sharing every minute and second.
星い...
I want to hear about anything concerning you.
夜の帳に隠れ
Hidden in the veil of night,
心キュンと赤く染まる
my heart beats and turns red,
好きかも...
maybe I'm in love.
ねえ、君に会いたい
Hey, I want to see you,
1分1秒、分け合いたい
sharing every minute and second.
僕の傍にはもう 君がいないと...
By my side, you are no longer here...
やっぱ、君に会いたい
I really want to see you,
1分1秒、駆け出したい
I want to rush over every minute and second.
赤い実が弾けた
The red fruit has burst open,
今すぐ君の傍に 行くよ
I'll go right to your side now.
こんばんは、どーもどーも！
Good evening, everyone!
ホロライブ4期生 角巻わためです！
It's Tsunomaki Watame from Hololive 4th generation!
みんな見に来てくれて、ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much everyone for coming to see me!
いやあ、君色ハナミズキどうだったかな？
So, how was "Kimiiro Hanamizuki"?
なんかこうやって3Dでね、みんなの前で歌うのは初めてなんですけど
It's my first time singing in 3D in front of everyone like this,
どうでしたでしょうか？
so how was it?
で、今日はね、君色ハナミズキということで
And today, since it's "Kimiiro Hanamizuki",
ハナミズキをなんと作っていただきました！イエーーーイ！
we actually had this "Hanamizuki" made for us!
見えるかな？
Can you see it?
おお、これは桜じゃないからね
Well, it's not cherry blossoms,
ハナミズキですからね、これ。
it's dogwood, you see!
どっからどう見てもハナミズキ 纯白のハナミズキですからね！
Dogwood, pure white dogwood, you know!
しかもこれ、見て！
And look at this, see?
これさ、ステージにさ、花びらがさ、当たるとさ、ぽわーんって！
If petals hit the stage, they do this trick!
ぽわーんって、ぴょん、ぴょんぽわーん！
They bounce off and go somewhere.
なんかちゃんとね、跳ね返ってね、どこか行くんだよ。
They bounce and head off somewhere.
これどこに行くのかな、異世界なのかな？
Where on earth do they go? Another world?
どうでもいっか！
Oh well!
今日はね、角巻わため超絶生誕祭2022というハッシュタグがありますので
Today is Tsunomaki Watame's "Chouzetsu Seitansai 2022" hashtag,
ぜひ！ぜひぜひ超絶ツイートみんなのおもしろ超絶、あ、おもしろくなくてもいいんだけど
so please, please post tons of funny/amazing tweets!
超絶ツイートをいっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい！してください。今すぐしてください。
Post lots of tweets now, okay?
Twitterやってない人は登録してください、お願いします。
If you don't use Twitter, please go register!
でもみんなね、たくさんスクショとかね、撮ったり
And I'd be so happy if you guys take lots of screenshots
いっぱい想いのたけをツイートしていただければ嬉しいなと思います。
and tweet your overflowing feelings!
あとで巡回しますからね、見ますからね。
I'll be checking them later!
いやあ、とうとうやってきたよ。
Well, finally it's here:
角巻わため今日で6時ゃい、もうね、小学生だね、羊の小学校行かなきゃ！
Tsunomaki Watame's Rock Day!
それでも
Even so...
一体この僕に何ができるって言うんだ
What more can I do?
窮屈な
So stifling.
過去にはの現実を変えるために何ができるの
What can I do to change this past reality?
人生の半分も
Even in half of this life,
僕はまだ生きてない
I haven't even lived yet.
絡まって　抱き合って　無意識に刻まれていく経験のタトゥー
Embracing, holding tight, and unknowingly carving tattoos of experience...
崖っぷちに立たされたときくなんだ僕の手を掴み、自分自身のありがたが初めて見えたんだ
At the dead end, when things got too painful, I reached out with my own hands.
初めて見えたんだ
I finally saw what I had.
もっと広いフィールドへもっと深い大きなどこへ、涙も効かない世界へ向かっていくだけ
Heading into a wider field, a deeper, bigger domain, toward a world where tears don't exist, just walking on.
教えて　強さの規定
Teaching me how to enforce my own strength,
自分貫くことかな　それとも自分さえ捨ててまで
Is it about pushing through, or abandoning even myself?
守るべきもの守ることでしか
Protecting what needs protecting by guarding it.
迷いの風が砂煙を上げる
The wind of hesitation raises a cloud of dust.
風の中あいつらは死ぬまで立ち続けなければいけないのさ
Those guys have to stand until they drop.
人は歩き続けてゆく　ただ生きてゆくために
People just keep walking, simply to keep living.
不完全なベータを振り返りながら進む
Looking back at an incomplete beta, glass breaks as I step forward.
始まりの合図を一人もう歩き出してるらしい
It seems someone has already started walking their own path since the very beginning.
僕は灰になるまで僕であり続けたい
I want to keep walking as myself until I turn to ash.
遠い昔どこから来たのと　遠い未来どこへ行くの　知らないまま投げ出され傷く前に時は終わるの
Coming from a distant past, and heading to a distant future, thrown away without even knowing where.
傷く前に時は終わるの
Before I even get hurt, will time run out?
始まりの合図を一人もう歩き出してるらしい
It seems someone has already started walking their own path since the very beginning.
僕は灰になるまで僕であり続けたい
I want to keep walking as myself until I turn to ash.
崖っぷちに立たされたときどんなが僕の手を掴み自分自身のありがたが初めて見えたんだ
At the dead end, when things got too painful, I reached out with my own hands.
初めて見えたんだ
I finally saw what I had.
もっと広いフィールドへもっと深い大きなドロへ、涙も効かない世界へ向かっていくだけ
Heading into a wider field, a deeper, bigger domain, toward a world where tears don't exist, just walking on.
僕は自分のことを走り出した
I ran through my own story.
いつか観ていた映画の中みたい
Like in a movie I watched sometime,
工事中の駅前 空へ背伸びしていくビルディング
under-construction station front, skyscrapers stretching their backs to the sky.
ヒールが鳴らすリズムと命の音が揃う
The rhythm marked by heels matches the sound of life.
あたしはまだ未完成で不完全
I'm still incomplete, imperfect,
起死回生のハウツー知ってるの
a dead-and-resurrected how-to, I know it.
今が一番若いの一番、
Right now is when I'm most youthful.
いつか観ていた映画の中みたい
Just like in a movie I used to watch,
工事中の駅前 空へ背伸びしていくビルディング
Skyscrapers reach up to the sky outside the station under construction.
ヒールが鳴らすリズムと命の音が揃う
The rhythm of my heels matches the sound of life.
あたしはまだ未完成で不完全
I'm still incomplete and imperfect,
起死回生のハウツー知ってるの
Resurrected, you know?
今が一番若いの一番、第六感、六感またがって
Right now is when I'm youngest—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, tell me,
今日は年甲斐もないことしたいの
Today I want to do something unusual.
予定にないこと第六感、六感教えて
Unexpected things—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, teach me.
物足りないの 引き合いたいよ 偶然とハートしたいの
I want to draw closer, let's connect by chance!
さあおいでませ誰彼 (I got it)
Come on everyone, come along (I got it)
道連れ世は情け (I got it)
Fellow travelers, the world is passionate (I got it)
ご覧召しませ この手立て
Look at this, taking a stand with this hand,
弱さ凌ぐ一手 智さにあり
Overcoming weakness relies on wisdom.
いつか話した予想とは違っているものさ
It's different from what we used to talk about,
そんな悲しまないでいいよ
So don't be so sad.
今が一番早いの第六感、六感あやかいて
Right now is the fastest—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, quicken,
疾走するハート嘘はつけないよ
A sprinting heart won't tell lies.
台詞にない言葉交換、交換教合って
Words not in the script—exchange, exchange, let me know,
そうくだらないを言い合いたい特別な感じたい
I want to say it together and feel something special.
産声をあげた日は理由もなく泣いていたのに
The day we were born, we cried for no reason,
今僕ら 泣くことすら上手くできずに
Now we can't even cry properly.
されどしかと死守せよ 品格と真似できぬプライドを
Let's fight to the end, dropping the pride that mocks our dignity,
せーので手放せよ 感覚で胸を打つものそれ以外を Crazy about this thing.
Letting go at the signal, hitting the heart with pure sensation, Crazy about this thing.
今が一番若いの一番第六感、六感またがって
Right now is when I'm youngest—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, ride on,
今日は年甲斐もないことしたいの
Today I want to do something unusual.
予定にないこと第六感、六感教えて
Unexpected things—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, teach me,
教えて、教えて
Teach me, teach me!
今最高潮なんです！第六感、六感またがって
Peak performance right now! Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, ride on,
このまま何処までいけるの
How far can we go just like this?
途方もないままで六感、六感教えて
With no destination in sight—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, teach me,
産声をもあげた日は
The day I raised my weeping voice,
わけもなく泣いていたのに
I was crying without any reason,
今僕ら 泣くことすら上手くできずに
Now we can't even cry properly.
されどしかと死守せよ品格と真似できぬプライドを
Let's fight to the end, dropping the pride that mocks our dignity,
せーので手放せよ感覚で胸を打つものそれ以外を
Letting go at the signal, hitting the heart with pure sensation,
Crazy about this thing.
今が一番若いの一番第六感、六感またがって
Right now is when I'm youngest—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, ride on,
今日は年甲斐もないことしたいの
Today I want to do something unusual.
予定にないこと第六感、六感教えて
Unexpected things—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, teach me,
教えて、教えて
Teach me, teach me!
今せい変わっちゃうんなんです第六感、六感またがって
Now it's changing—why? I want to connect by chance!
このままどこまでいけるの
How far can we go just like this?
底も無いままゼロ感六感教えてもう揺るがない
With no end in sight—Sixth Sense, Sixth Sense, teach me,
この速度は
This speed won't waver anymore,
急峻と疾走しとれ
Sudden and rapid stride.
はい、ということでね、あれ？カメラ、カメラどこかな？
So, you know, um... Camera, camera, where is it?
あれ？カメラさん、ちゃんと撮ってくれないと…
Camera-san, if you don't film properly...
こまる！うららららららららら！
Come on! I'll curse you!
困るよなー！
How annoying!
ん、みんな何にも見てないね。
Well, nobody's looking anyway.
ん？誕生日だから許されるんだよ。
Well, it's my birthday, so I'm forgiven!
わためは悪くないよねー！せいっ！
Watame is not bad, right?
一緒に、せいっ！悪くないよねー！
Together, say! Not bad, right?
いぇーい！
Yay!
ということで、えーボタンちゃんと、Hemi-Sophia、
So, um, Botan-chan and Hemi-Sophia,
そして、えー一緒に歌ってみたかった、おかゆ先ぱんを
And, uh, Okayu-sempai, whom I wanted to sing with...
おかゆんと第六感を歌って踊らせていただきました！
Okayun and I sang "The Sixth Sense" and danced,
うれしー！
Yay!
大好きなボタンちゃんと、あとおかゆんと
My favorite Botan-chan and Okayun,
一緒に歌ったり踊ったりできて、最後にハッピーなんじゃー！
we could sing and dance together, and finally, Happy Nanja!
ダブルラリアット！
Double Lariat!
油断していただろう、みんな！
I got careless, didn't I, everyone?
いや、うれしかったな。
Yeah, I'm so happy.
ま、ボタンちゃんはね、
Well, Botan-chan, you know,
いつもコラボしてもらったりとか、
always collaborates with me,
あとこうやって、あの記念配信とかもね、毎回きてもらったりとか
and also comes to my commemorative streams every time,
あのしてくれているんだけど、おかゆんは結構わための配信でこうやって一緒にやるっていうのは
so for Okayun to come and do this together with Watame's stream...
珍しいんじゃないかなと思います。
I think it's pretty rare, don't you?
いや、おかゆんの歌めっちゃ好きで、
I really love Okayun's singing,
もぐもぐYummyとか、いろいろデタバレ猫とかね、いろいろ聞いてるんだけど、
"Mogu Mogu Yummy" and various Databare Neko,
こうやって歌って、しかもね、ダンスまで一緒に踊ってもらえて
to actually sing together and even dance like this...
めちゃくちゃハッピー！どうだった？どうだった？かっこよかった？かっこよかった？
It's super happy! How was it? How was it? Was it cool? Was it cool?
どうだった？かっこよかった？
How was it? Was it cool?
うれしー！
Yay!
いや、まだね、実はゲストがいまして、まだまだいまして、
Well, still, actually we have guests,
えーさっきの二人もね、この後もまだ、
the two from earlier as well—this is...
おっととこの先は言えないな。
Oops, I can't say what's next.
では次は、
So next is...
めちゃくちゃ珍しいゲストだと、
A super rare guest!
思い出します
I remember it well.
多分ね、ほぼほぼコラボしたことないんじゃないかなと、思いますよ。
I think we've probably almost never collaborated before.
いろんな方とね。
With various people, you know.
では、行きましょう。次のコラボ相手は、
Now then, let's go. The next collaboration partner is...
こちら！
Right here!
意中の瞬き 火照りだして
I'm obsessed with your blinking and it's got me hot and bothered,
13 14 腐った調味料 スパイスでね
13, 14, with some rotten seasoning and spice,
痛いな この手に ぐさりだして
it hurts, sinking deep into these hands,
30 40 狂ったように スマイルでね
30, 40, smiling like I've gone crazy.
リンド リンド 愛を重ねて
Lindo, lindo, pile up the love,
リンド リンド 耳飾り
lindo, lindo, earrings,
リンド リンド いっそ隠して
lindo, lindo, why not hide it away,
リンド きっとバラバラバララララ
lindo, surely it'll break into pieces, la la la!
l l life ユウエミー e e eye 故に
l l life you and me e e eye, due to it,
バッドプレイ 引っ張って バラバラバラララ
this bad play is drawn out into many pieces, la la la!
k k knife ユウエミー e e eye 既に
k k knife you and me e e eye, it's already—
底見れ ば 悪 バラバラバラララ
if you look at the bottom, the evil is in pieces, la la la!
l l life e e eye
穿つ この目で
With this pierced eye...
絶えず その手で
without end, with those hands...
瞬きでさえ 惜しいから
I don't want to waste a single blink.
見えぬ 姿で
In an unseeable form,
あらぬ 素振りで
with an unforeseen attitude,
放つ 言葉で 溢れて
overflowing with the words you released.
リンド リンド 愛を数えて
Lindo, lindo, count up the love,
リンド リンド 耳障り
lindo, lindo, it's cacophonous,
リンド リンド きっと託して
lindo, lindo, surely entrust it to me,
リンド きっとバラバラバララララ
lindo, surely it'll break into pieces, la la la!
l l life ユウエミー e e eye 故に
l l life you and me e e eye, due to it,
バッドグレイ 1つ バラバラバラララ
the singular bad gray breaks into pieces, la la la!
k k knife ユウエミー e e eye 既に
k k knife you and me e e eye, it's already—
底知れ ば 悪 飽き絶えて
if you come to know of the bottom, it's evil; if I get so bored and end it,
l l life e e eye
ひとりぼっちだ
I'll be alone,
酷く 甘美だ
and it'll be awfully delightful.
なぜ
Why?
誰が待ってる
Who is waiting?
はあ、あい、かっこよかったな。
Whew, Ai, that was so cool.
あれ？さっきまで誰かと一緒に歌ってたような気がするんだけど、黒っぽい、黒っぽいキツネっぽい人と歌ってたような気がするんだけど、キツネなのか人なのかちょっとよくわかんないけど、
Huh? I feel like I was singing with someone just now... A blackish, fox-like person, I feel like I was singing with a fox-like or human person, I'm not quite sure if it's a fox or a human, but...
あれ？みんな、
Huh? Everyone,
あれ？わためだけ見えてた？
Huh? Could only Watame be seen?
え、そうなの？わためだけ見えてたの？
Eh, really? Only Watame was visible?
あれ、おかしいな。しかもなんか誰かと似てたんだよな。
Huh, that's strange. Plus, she looked a lot like someone.
似てたんだよな、誰かと。誰かと、なんか誰か来そうな気がするんだけど、
She looked like someone. With someone, I feel like someone's coming...
あれ、なんかチラチラ見られてる気がする。あれ？
Huh, I feel like I'm being glanced at. Huh?
え、誰かいたんだい？誰と歌っていたんだい？
Eh, was someone there? Who were you singing with?
さっきの、吹雪ちゃんのね、黒っぽい、
Just now, Fubuki-chan's, you know, blackish...
ええ、いい、吹雪ちゃん？
Eh? Good, Fubuki-chan?
え、白髪の思いっきり出てないよ？
Eh, my white hair wasn't showing at all, you know?
え、待って。吹雪ちゃん分散したの？
Eh, wait. Did Fubuki-chan split up?
分散してないはず。あれ、おかしいの？
She shouldn't have split up. Huh, is that strange?
色違いだった。
They were different colors.
Different colors!
サーカス、サーカスの人だ！
Circus, they're circus people!
え、待って！カンカンダンス！サーカスダンスして！
Eh, wait! Can-can dance! Do the circus dance!
バカタレでも並んで、バカタレでも一緒、ほらサーカス！
Even Bakatare lined up, Bakatare together—look, the circus!
そう、サーカスダンスの日はね。
That's right, the day for circus dances, you know.
サーカスダンスのひなのだ！そうだった！
It's the day for circus dances! That's right!
え、誰？名前、名前、誰だっけ？名前、もう記憶なくなっちゃった。記憶なくなっちゃったら、わため。
Eh, who? Name, name, who was it again? Name, I already lost my memory. If I lose my memory, Watame...
おいちょ、え、白上、吹雪と、知らんぬい、フレアと、
Oi-cho, eh, Shirakami Fubuki, and Shiranui Flare, and...
お前ら、これがだよ。お前らやれよ！
Hey you guys, this is it. You guys do it!
サーカスダンスやってよ！
Do the circus dance!
やんないよ。
We won't do it.
やんないの？プレゼントにやってよ。今日何の日か知ってんの？
You won't? Do it as a present. Do you know what day today is?
お、まも、わため、
Oh, ma-mo, Watame...
知ってんの？今日何の日か知ってんの？だ、こっちも記憶喪失だ。
Do you know? Do you know what day today is? Ah, we've also got amnesia.
なんだろな。なんでわかんないの？
What could it be? Why don't you know?
わため、教えて、今日は何の日？
Watame, tell us, what day is today?
今日は、あの、おた、おた、おたおた、おたおた、おたおた服、おたまじゃくし、おたまじゃくしじゃあ！
Today is, um, ota, ota, ota-ota, ota-ota, ota-ota clothes, tadpole, tadpole—no!
Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday
Happy Birthday Dear Watame
Happy Birthday to you
嬉しい！
Yay!
なんか人数増えちゃったんだい？
Wait, did our numbers increase?
六ちゃい？
Six years old?
六ちゃい！六ちゃい！六ちゃい！
Six years old! Six years old!
二百年六ちゃい！
200 years old, six years old!
ランドセル背負わなきゃいけないじゃん
Doesn't she have to wear a school backpack?
ランドセル何色？ ランドセル？
What color randoseru? A randoseru?
何色にしようかね？何色が似合う？赤？
What color should we pick? What suits her? Red?
赤とかピンクとか、でもピンクいいね
Red or pink... But pink is nice.
六年生になったらさ、絶対ピンクはだめだと思うんだよね。茶色とかの方がいいと思うんだよね。
By sixth grade, pink is definitely no good. Brown is probably better.
ああ、茶色とかね。
Ah, brown or something.
茶色だったらさ、全然六年生言われてもピンクはね、恥ずてなると思うんだよね。
With brown, even as a sixth grader... pink would be embarrassing.
あー、確かに。
Ah, true.
恥ずかしくなっちゃうかな。
You'd probably get embarrassed.
おしゃれだね。
That's fashionable.
おしゃれだね、茶色は。茶色可愛いじゃん。
Yeah, brown is fashionable. Brown is cute, right?
ねえ。
Right?
ランドセルつけてもらおうか、じゃあ。
Let's have her wear a randoseru then.
ランドセルつけてもらう？
Have her wear one?
いいね。
Nice.
いいねいいね。
Nice, nice.
やばい、なんか嬉しくなくなってきたな！嬉しい！嬉しいね！
Oh no, I'm starting to feel less happy! Yay! I'm so happy!
我々、お祝いに来ただけなんだからさ、そろそろ帰ろうか。
We just came here to celebrate, so we should head home soon.
いやいやいや、バイバイ！
No no no, bye-bye!
ちょっと待ってちょっと待って！
Wait a second, wait a second!
よいしょよいしょよいしょよいしょ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
なんだよ、せっかく！
What is this, after we came all this way!
せっかく来たならさ、ほら見てごらんなさ、ここ。
Since you came all this way, look over here!
どこですか、ここ。
Where is this?
わあ、ステージだわ！
Wow, it's a stage!
ほら！みんな待ってるよ！
Look! Everyone's waiting!
すごい、待ってる！
Amazing, they're waiting!
本当だ、みんな振って待っててくれてる。
It's true, everyone's waving and waiting for us.
本当だ。ステージ行こう。
That's right. Let's go to the stage.
待ってんね！待ってんね！
They're waiting! They're waiting!
あそこのちっちゃい子、あ、いいね、可愛い。あそこの緑のお姉さん、すっごい素敵！
That little kid over there—ah, nice, cute. The green lady over there is so wonderful!
ドリー？
Dory?
ドリーかな？
Is that Dory?
ドリー頑張れ！ドリー、ドレスの裾が危ない、裾を下げてください！
Do your best, Dory! Dory, your dress hem is dangerous, lower your hem!
ドリー、危ない、裾を下げて！
Dory, it's dangerous, lower your hem!
ドリーちゃん危ないよ。
Dory-chan, it's dangerous.
ドリーちゃん食べちゃおう！
Let's eat Dory-chan!
駄目だよ、駄目駄目。
No way, no way.
いや、あれやろうよ。
Hey, let's do that.
あれ？バンドとかやりてえんだよ。演奏やりたくない？
Huh? I want to do a band. Don't you want to play instruments?
え、バンドやりたいんだよ！バンドやりたい！
Eh, I want to do a band! I want to do a band!
バンドやりたいねえ！やりたい！いいね！
We want to do a band! Want to do it! Nice!
楽器ないのでも。あ、楽器確かに。
Even without instruments. Ah, instruments, true.
なんだろうね、え、どうしようか。
I wonder what, eh, what should we do?
何やりたい？やっぱりギターがいいな。
What do you want to do? Guitar would be nice.
えー、じゃあ、穴が足りないじゃん。
Eh, well, aren't there not enough holes?
え、でも、よりたいな。
Eh, but, I want to.
でもこの世にんでしょ？
But in this world, right?
そうだよ。
That's right.
わためはやっぱボーカルでしょ？
Watame is vocals, right?
そしたらさ、えっと、ドラム？
Then, um, drums?
お、ドラム？ いやでもさ、ドラムさすがになくないよな。
Oh, drums? No, but drums, surely there aren't none.
このへんとことかにさ、ドラムあったらいいんだけどな。
If there were drums around here, that'd be great.
まあ、出ないかなあ。ドラムないかなあ。
Well, I wonder if they'll appear. I wonder if there are drums.
出たけど、出たけど、おー！
It appeared, it appeared, oh!
すごい！
Amazing!
え？出た！出た！出た！
Eh? It appeared! It appeared!
お、出たー！
Oh, it appeared!
え？いんですこ、そんなドラム弾けないけど、引いちゃってもいいですか？
Eh? Is it okay? I can't really play drums, but is it okay if I play it?
いやいいよいいよ、あ、スティック持ってる！スティック持ってる！あ、この人たちドラムの達人やってる人いらっしゃるわけの。
No, it's fine. Ah, holding sticks! These people are drum masters.
なんかここらへんだって、もういるじゃん、ここに。
Like, around here, there's already people here.
ほら、ここにドンって来たらさ、それかっこいいじゃん、たぶんさ、その。
Look, if you come in with a bang here, that's cool, probably.
いや、でも流石になあ。
No, but really.
いや、でもね、ドラムは出たけど、出たけど。
No, but, drums appeared, but they appeared.
おー！すげえ！すごい！
Oh! Amazing! Amazing!
出たやんけ！すごい！
It's out! Amazing!
あるじゃん！出とるよ！すごい！
There are some! It's out! Amazing!
すげえこれ！
This is amazing!
すごい！すごいいいよ！
Amazing! Amazing, good!
えじゃ、残りのもじゃ、ギター、ギター欲しいな！ギター、ギター！
Eh then, for the rest, guitar, I want a guitar! Guitar, guitar!
ギター、ギター！
Guitar, guitar!
じゃあー、おっ！
Well then, oh!
来た！
It came!
あ！出てきた！出てきた！上から来るぞ！
Ah! It came out! It's coming from above!
気をつけて！上から来るぞ！
Careful! It's coming from above!
上から来るぞ！すごい！
It's coming from above! Amazing!
え、ねえ、わため、ここにねマイクあるよ！
Eh, hey, Watame, there's a mic right here!
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
マイクある？
There's a mic?
本当だ！
Really!
じゃ、わため、ボーカルでマイク。
Then Watame, vocals, mic.
まあ、わため消去法でマイクだもん。
Well, Watame got the mic by process of elimination.
消去法でマイク。消去法でボーカルの人が。
Mic by process of elimination. A vocal person.
よかったですね！
That's great!
わため、マイク！
Watame, mic!
じゃ、これでじゃあ、バンドが、あ、できるね！
So with this, the band can, oh, be formed!
できるね！
We can do it!
じゃあ、練習してよ！やってよ！
Well then, practice! Do it!
じゃあ、ちょっと叩いてみよっか！
Well then, let's try hitting it a bit!
叩いてよ！チューニング！
Hit it! Tuning!
変えるの？
Change it?
ちょっとだ、叩いてみてよ！
Just, try hitting it!
かっ...
Ka...
音鳴ってる鳴ってる鳴ってる！
Sound is playing, playing, playing!
え、ちゃんと動いてるんだよね？
Eh, it's actually moving, right?
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
聞こえるかな？
うん。ドドン、ドドン！
Yeah. Dodon, dodon!
最高やん、それ！
That's the best!
なんか叩いてる？
Are you hitting something?
なんかドラムらしくない音してません？
Isn't it making a sound that doesn't really sound like drums?
なんかゲーム大会してる人がいる。あ、この人達やってる人いらっしゃるわけの。
There's someone having a game tournament. Ah, these people are doing it.
お！すごい！すごい！
Oh! Amazing! Amazing!
いいよ！すごいよ！
Good! Amazing!
なんかかましてくださーいよ！それっぽく叩くんで！
Bring it on! Hit it like you mean it!
それっぽく？それっぽくガチなんだよ！
Like it? It's seriously serious!
マジでやってる？ガチでやってんだよ！ガチで！
Doing it for real? We're doing it for real! For real!
じゃあ、DJやってよ！さあ、ガチなんだよ！
Then, do DJ! Come on, it's serious!
わための誕生日の日よ、みんなさ。
It's Watame's birthday, everyone.
確かに！
True!
じゃ、ガチDJやってよ！
So do a serious DJ!
やっ...やってよ！
Do... do it!
機材音痴なんだよ！
I'm hopeless with equipment!
お前知ってんだろ！
You know about this!
前回ガチじゃなかったのか！
Wasn't it serious last time!
くらっせ！
Eat this!
もっとあれだったら...もっとあれだったら...
If it were more... if it were more...
じゃ、待て！待て！
Wait, wait!
まだ電源通ってないんだよ！
The power isn't even on yet!
なんだよ！
What the heck!
まだ電源入ってないんだよ！
The power isn't even on yet!
まだ入ってないのか！
It's not in yet!
そうなんだよ！
That's right!
ごめんごめん！
Sorry, sorry!
そうかそうか！
Ah, I see, I see!
じゃ、ギターは？
Then what about the guitar?
ギターってかっこいいやつやってよ
Play something cool on the guitar!
うん、やってよ
Yeah, do it.
なんかラーメンできそう
Looks like we can make ramen...
ラーメンできそうじゃん、こんな感じだけど。でもね、ほんまは本気でやろうかなとじゃあ。
It looks like we can make ramen like this. But you know, let's do it seriously.
すまなそう思いますのでね、じゃあバンドお願いしてもいいですか?
I feel bad about it, so can I ask for a band?
かっこいいのやりたいんだけど、そういう感じじゃなくなるのかな?どうなんだろね、2人の曲。なんだろうね。
I want to do something cool, but will it not feel like that? I wonder how the song will be.
じゃあもう準備してきますか、我々はね。ちょっと早く練習しようか。ね、ちょっと改めてチューニングしにじゃあ。
Shall we get ready then? Let's practice quickly. Let's tune our instruments again.
はい、戻ろうかな。
Yeah, shall we go back?
練習するよ、おまるちゃん。いくよ。
Let's practice, Omaru-chan. Here we go.
play the world! feat. PABLO
[Title: play the world! feat. PABLO]
singing ya! 合図 響いた
Singing ya! The signal echoed...
play the world! つまり連勝確定
Play the world! Meaning victory is guaranteed,
play the world! 受けて立つ余裕じゃん
Play the world! We've got room to take you on,
play the world! かなり興奮してる
Play the world! We're getting pretty excited,
let's play the world!
singing ya! 合図 響いた play the world!
Singing ya! The signal echoed, play the world!
つまり連勝確定 play the world!
Meaning victory is guaranteed, play the world!
胸に聞く即回答 play the world!
Asking our hearts for answers, play the world!
これが自由の入り口 叫べ
This is the entrance to freedom, shout...
my name is !! 従順に
My name is!! Follow me obediently,
follow me 後悔はさせない
we won't let you regret it!
my name is !! my name is !!
My name is!! My name is!!
人生は続編へ スピンオフなんかじゃないぜ
Life is heading into a sequel, it's no spin-off!
カットアウト？ナンセンス play the world!
Cut out? Nonsense, play the world!
ツナガリグルーブして go around
Connect and groove, go around!
全部大切だって捨てられないか？
Can't you abandon anything, thinking it's all precious?
目には目 声には声 愛には愛
An eye for an eye, a voice for a voice, love for love!
基本中の基本だわかってろ！
It's the absolute basics, get it through your head!
今からゲンミツに play the world!
Strictly speaking from now on, play the world!
目をそらすなよ！ok, 叫べ my name is !!
Don't look away! Ok, shout my name is!!
最高だって信じたい
We want to believe it's the best!
生まれ落ちたからには最後まで
Since we were born into this world, all the way to the end—
beat me beat me そうだよな
Beat me, beat me, that's right, isn't it?
この世界を遊び尽くせ
Play this world to the fullest!
愛し抜くと決めたよ
I decided to love through it all,
そして愛される覚悟も決めたんだ
and I've also resolved to be loved.
これが僕だ止まれない
This is who I am, I can't stop!
つまり自由の入り口 叫べ my name is !!
Meaning the entrance to freedom, shout my name is!!
人生は続編へ
Life is heading into a sequel!
give and take? haha 100倍にして返すよ
Give and take? Haha. I'll return it a hundredfold,
play the world! 感謝感激も不要じゃない？
Play the world! Don't we even need gratitude and excitement?
それよりも革命を見ようじゃない
Rather than that, shouldn't we witness a revolution?
i can say !! 嫌味って何味？
I can say!! What flavor is sarcasm?
知らなくてもいいや関係ないし
It's fine even if I don't know, it doesn't matter.
噛み砕いて飲み干せば ah ほら歌になる
If you chew it up and swallow it down, ah, it turns into a song.
最高を味わいたい いつも同じじゃつまらないぜ
I want to taste the best, staying the same is boring!
beat me beat me そうだよな
Beat me, beat me, that's right, isn't it?
ほら希望が有り余ってる
Look, hope is overflowing.
変幻自在に迫る 光の色した高揚の sweet spot
The sweet spot of euphoria approaching with changing colors like light.
ワクワクが止まらない つまり自由の入り口
The excitement won't stop, meaning the entrance to freedom!
生まれ変わる事恐れない 無くしたって進むしかない
Not afraid of being reborn, having lost it, we can only move forward!
生き続けろ絶対 何がなんでもそうだろう！
Keep living absolutely, no matter what happens!
運命はいつも僕の 先でそっと手招いてるんだ
Destiny is always beckoning to us just ahead.
諦めるな逃げるな
Don't give up, don't run away!
これが gateway to freedom oh yeah
This is gateway to freedom, oh yeah.
最高だって信じたい
We want to believe it's the best!
生まれ落ちたからには最後まで
Since we were born into this world, all the way to the end—
beat me beat me そうだよな
Beat me, beat me, that's right, isn't it?
この世界を遊び尽くせ
Play this world to the fullest!
続編を始めよう 自由への続編だ my name is !!
Let's start the sequel! It's the sequel to freedom, my name is!!
最高だって信じたい
We want to believe it's the best!
生まれ落ちたからには最後まで
Since we were born into this world, all the way to the end—
beat me beat me そうだよな
Beat me, beat me, that's right, isn't it?
この世界を遊び尽くせ
Play this world to the fullest!
愛し抜くと決めたよ
I decided to love through it all,
そして愛される覚悟も決めたんだ
and I've also resolved to be loved.
これが僕だ止まれない
This is who I am, I can't stop!
つまり自由の入り口 叫べ my name is !!
Meaning the entrance to freedom, shout my name is!!
my name is !! my name is !! 人生は続編へ
My name is!! My name is!! Life is heading into a sequel!
give and take? haha 100倍にして返すよ
Give and take? Haha. I'll return it a hundredfold,
play the world! 感謝感激も不要じゃない？
Play the world! Don't we even need gratitude and excitement?
それよりも革命を見ようじゃない I can say !!
Rather than that, shouldn't we witness a revolution? I can say!!
嫌味って何味？知らなくてもいいや関係ないし
What flavor is sarcasm? It's fine even if I don't know, it doesn't matter.
噛み砕いて飲み干せば ah ほら歌になる
If you chew it up and swallow it down, ah, it turns into a song.
最高を味わいたい いつも同じじゃつまらないぜ
I want to taste the best, staying the same is boring!
beat me beat me そうだよな
Beat me, beat me, that's right, isn't it?
singing ya! 合図 響いた play the world!
singing ya! The signal echoed, play the world!
つまり 連戦 確定 play the world!
Meaning consecutive battles guaranteed, play the world!
この世界を遊び尽くせ
Play this world to the fullest!
続編を始めよう
Let's start the sequel.
自由への入り口
The entrance to freedom,
叫べ my name is!!
shout my name is!!
従順に follow me 後悔はさせない
Follow obediently, I won't let you regret it.
my name is!! my name is!!
人生は続編へスピンオフ なんかじゃないぜ
Life is a spin-off to a sequel, it's not just that!
カットアウト? ナンセンス play the world!
Cut out? Nonsense, play the world!
ツナガリ グルーヴ して go around
Connecting, grooving and go around,
最高だって信じたい
I want to believe it's the best.
生まれ落ちたからには最後まで
Since I was born into this world, right to the end.
beat me beat me そうだよな
beat me beat me, that's right,
この世界を遊び尽くせ
play this world to the fullest!
愛し抜くと決めたよ そして愛される覚悟も決めたんだ
I decided to love through it all, and decided to be ready to be loved.
これが僕だ止まれない
This is who I am, I can't stop,
つまり自由の入り口 叫べ my name is!!
meaning the entrance to freedom, shout my name is!!
嗚呼、いつものように 過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
Ah, yawning at days passing by just like always,
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も 渋谷の街に朝が降る
crossing noisy nights, morning falls on Shibuya's streets today too.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち つまらないな
A somewhat hollow feeling, how boring.
でもそれでいい そんなもんさ これでいい
But that's fine, that's just how it is, this is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let your true voice, which you unknowingly hid, echo, come on.
見ないふりしていても 確かにあるそこに
Even if you pretend not to see it, it is definitely there.
感じたままに描く 自分で選んだその色で
Drawing as you feel, with the colors you chose yourself.
眠い空気纏う朝に 訪れた青い世界
An azure world visited on a morning wrapped in sleepy air.
好きなものを好きと言う 怖くて仕方ないけれど 本当の自分 出会えた気がしたんだ
Saying what you like is so scary, but it felt like I met my true self.
嗚呼、手を伸ばれば 伸びるほどに 遠くへゆく
Ah, the more I reach out, the further away it goes.
想うようにいかない、今日も また慌ただしくもがいている
Nothing goes as planned, struggling busily again today.
悔しい気持ちも ただ情けなくて 涙が出る
Regretful feelings just feel pathetic, making me tear up.
踏み込むほど 苦しくなる 痛くもなる
The more I step in, the more painful and agonizing it gets.
感じたままに進む 自分で選んだこの道を
Moving forward as I feel, down this path I chose myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に しがみついた青い誓い
An azure vow I clung to on a night rubbing heavy eyelids.
好きなことを続けること それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
Continuing what you love isn't just "fun".
本当にできる? 不安になるけど
Can I really do it? I get anxious, but
何枚でも ほら何枚でも
no matter how many times, come on, no matter how many times.
自信がないから描いてきたんだ 何回でも ほら何回でも
Because I lack confidence, I've drawn countless times, come on, countless times.
周りを見渡して 誰と比べたって 僕にしかできないことはなんだ
Looking around and comparing myself to others, what is only I can do?
今でも自信なんか無い それでも
Even now I have no confidence, but still...
感じたことない気持ち 知らずにいた思い
Knowing feelings I've never felt, thoughts I didn't know.
あの日踏み出して 初めて感じたこの瞳も全部
That day I stepped out and felt this pain for the very first time.
好きなものと向き合うことで 触れた まだ小さな光
Touching a still small light by facing what I love.
全てをかけて描く 自分にしか出せない色で
Drawing with everything I have, in colors only I can produce.
朝も夜も走り続け 見つけ出した青い光
Running through morning and night, finding that azure light.
好きなものと向き合うこと 今だって怖いことだけど
Facing what I love is still a scary thing, but
もう今はあの日の透明な僕じゃない
now I'm no longer the transparent me of that day.
ありのままのかけがえのない僕だ
I am myself, irreplaceable.
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let your true voice, which you unknowingly hid, echo, come on.
見ないふりしていても 確かにあるそこに
Even if you pretend not to see it, it is definitely there.
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ、さあ
Let your true voice, which you unknowingly hid, echo, come on.
ダー、いつもの様に
Ah, like every day I see
過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
Another day repeats, I'm yawning all the time
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も
Past the bustling night, today too
君の中に
deep within you.
わあ！
Yay!
プレイザワールドと群青、楽しかったなー！
'Play the World' and 'Gunjou' were so much fun!
みんなも楽しかったですか？
Did you all have fun too?
かっこよかった？
Was I cool?
お、切ない気持ちになった？
Oh, did it make you feel a bit emotional?
いや、みんなコメント見えてますからね。
Man, I can see everyone's comments, you know.
ありがとう！楽しんでもらえたようで嬉しいー！
Thank you! I'm so glad you enjoyed it!
まあ、こんなところでちょっとみんなにお伝えしたいとこ、あ、こ、こと、こと、ことがあるんだけど！
Well, there's something I'd like to tell everyone right about now—um, an announcement!
感じた？
Did you feel it?
え、ちょっとだけ告知をさせていただいてもいいでしょうかー？
Um, would it be okay if I made a little announcement?
いやー！
Yeah!
いいよ！ありがとう！
Sure! Thank you!
では、いきます！え、まず1、
Well then, here we go! First off,
角巻わため超絶生誕グッズ！
Tsunomaki Watame's Superb Birthday Merch!
この後発売になります！販売開始ー！イェーイ！
It goes on sale right after this! Sales start now! Yay!
内容は、
The contents are:
ラバーマットとマフラーとスリッパの3点で全部セットをかっていただいた方には、
A rubber mat, muffler, and slippers—a set of three. Those who buy the full set will get—
直筆サイン入りポストカードと特典ボイスが付きまーす！イェーイ！
a postcard with a handwritten signature and bonus voice clips! Yay!
毎年のことではあるんですけど、え、サインは全部書かせていただきます！
It's an annual tradition, but um, I'll be signing every single one by hand!
数量限定ではございません。
There is no quantity limit.
なので、みんな争わずにね、ゆっくり買ってくださいね。
So everyone, please don't fight over them and take your time buying them.
え、そして、え、なんで、今、これから夏なのに、マフラー？スリッパ？なんでなんでなんで？って思っている方もいらっしゃると思うんですが、
And also, um... why a muffler and slippers when it's about to be summer? Some of you might be wondering why, why, why?
あの、受注生産のため、みんなのもとに届く期間がね、ちょっとかかってしまうので、
Well, because they're made-to-order, it takes a little while for them to reach everyone,
名探偵わためはそれを見越して、マフラーやスリッパをいま作ったんですね！
so Detective Watame anticipated that and made the muffler and slippers right now!
これ賢い！賢い！賢いね！
That's smart! Smart! So smart!
そう、なので多分涼しくなってきた頃か、寒くなってきたなって頃にマフラーとかスリッパとかね、届くと思いますので、
So yeah, I think they'll arrive around when it starts getting cooler or cold.
今からどうでしょうかあなたのお首元に、これでお一緒に冬を過ごせたら嬉しいなって思います！
How about wrapping it around your neck starting now? I'd be so happy if we could spend the winter together!
ラバーマットも、ふーみママがめっちゃ可愛く書いてくれたんですよ！
And the rubber mat was drawn super cute by Fuumi-mama!
なんと、わためとも一緒に、あの、あるとかないとかあるとか、お、ま、いつも一緒だからね、わためとわためとはね、うん、ね！
It features Watame and... wait, is there or isn't there? Well, we're always together anyway, Watame and Watame, yeah!
なので、ぜひあなたのおうちに置いてください！お願いします！
So please put it in your homes! Please!
そして、特典ボイスは特典なので買ってからのお楽しみです！
And the bonus voice is a surprise after you buy it!
よかったらみんなどしどし買ってくださーい！
If you'd like, everyone, please go ahead and buy lots!
え、そして、え、2、去年行った、角巻わためファーストソロライブ、わためナイトフィーバーのBDパッケージが6月29日に発売になります！イェーイ！
And, um, second! Tsunomaki Watame's 1st Solo Live, Watame Night Fever, held last year, its Blu-ray package will go on sale on June 29th! Yay!
もうね予約は開始してるんですけど、ぜひよかったら買ってみてください！よろしくお願いします！
Reservations are already open, so please check it out if you'd like! Thank you!
ということで、告知パートはこれで一旦終わりだ！一旦ね！
So with that, the announcement part is over for now! For now, yeah!
ちょっと次の曲着替えてきてもいいですか？
Would it be okay if I went and changed for the next song?
え、そんな待たせないから大丈夫、そんな待たせない大丈夫、すぐ着替えるから大丈夫だよ！ほら！
Uh, I won't make you wait long, it's fine, I won't make you wait long, it's fine, I'll change right away! Look!
今脱いで、脱いで、脱いで、吐いて、脱いで、吐いて、脱いで、よし！
Taking it off now, taking it off, taking it off, panting, taking it off, panting, taking it off, alright!
じゃーん！ソロライブの時に着させていただいたライブ衣装です！
Ta-da! This is the live outfit I wore during my solo live!
今日はこれを着て、初めて歌う歌をみんなに歌いたいと思います。心を込めて歌いたいと思いますので、みんな、
Today, wearing this, I want to sing a song I've never sung before for everyone. I want to sing it with all my heart, so everyone,
心して聞いてください！
please listen with all your heart!
マイソングの曲を作ってくださった
Horie Shota-san, who made my song,
ホリエショウタさんが曲を書いてくれました！
has written a song for me!
わための新しいオリジナルソング 『夢見る羊』！
Watame's new original song, "Yumemiru Hitsuji"!
叶えたい未来へ
Toward the future I want to fulfill,
心の準備 OK ？
is your heart ready? OK?
さあ、一歩踏み出して
Now, take a step forward,
いっせーの、せ！
Ready, set, go!
夢見る羊
[Title: Yumemiru Hitsuji]
真っ白な羊に命が宿って
Life dwells within a pure white sheep,
目覚めたんだこの大きな世界で
and it has awakened in this vast world.
何をしようか どこに行こうか
What should I do? Where should I go?
冒険は始まった
The adventure has begun.
フラフラな足取りで弱々しく
With wobbly footsteps and feebly,
声も震えて上手く鳴けない
my voice trembles and I can't bleat right.
そんな自分がやるせない
I feel so helpless with myself.
自信喪失気味です
I'm losing all my confidence.
でも時間は進む
Yet time keeps moving forward,
気持ちばかり焦る
and my emotions just rush ahead.
「ゆっくりでいいから 泣いてちゃだめだよ」
"It's okay to take your time, but you mustn't cry."
叶えたい未来へ
Toward the future I want to fulfill,
心の準備 OK ？
is your heart ready? OK?
さあ、一歩踏み出して
Now, take a step forward,
1 、 2 、 3
One, two, three!
僕は君と出会って 自信を取り戻して
Meeting you helped me regain my confidence,
ゆっくりと今 確かに歩み出した
and now, I've taken a steady step forward.
夢を見つけて いくつも抱きかかえて
Finding dreams and embracing so many of them,
君と話した 未来を掴みに行こう
let's go seize the future we talked about.
一緒に 隣 歩いて行こう
Let's walk side by side together.
まっすぐな羊に迷いはないのさ
A straightforward sheep has no hesitations.
走り出したら急には止まれない
Once she starts running, she can't stop suddenly.
周りを巻き込む そんな羊に今
Now, into that sheep who draws everyone in,
なれる気がしたんだ
I felt like I could transform.
明日を迎えたくない日も
Even on days I don't want tomorrow to come,
アンニュイな朝も昼も夜も
on languid mornings, afternoons, and nights,
半分こして 食べ合って夢見よう
let's share and eat together, dreaming away.
このまま 一緒に 夜に溶けて
Melting into the night together just like this.
僕は君と出会って 自信を取り戻して
Meeting you helped me regain my confidence,
泥まみれでも 何度も走り出した
and covered in mud, I started running again and again.
夢を見つけて いくつも抱きかかえて
Finding dreams and embracing so many of them,
君と話した 未来を掴みに行こう
let's go seize the future we talked about.
見たこともない 景色広がる世界へ 連れて行くよ
I'll take you to a world with scenery you've never seen before.
一緒に ずっと 歩いて行こう
Let's keep walking together forever.
同じ未来へ
Toward the same future.
あーー！水飲んでいっか。
Ahhh! Should I drink some water?
ちょっと水飲んでもいいですか？
Do you mind if I drink a little water?
もう、みんなどうだったかな？
How did everyone find it?
もう、ドキドキしたで…
Man, my heart was pounding...
あ、息切れる。あー、まいっか。
Ah, I'm out of breath. Oh well.
ただいま！
I'm back!
いまお披露目した『夢見る羊』ですが、
As for the song "Yumemiru Hitsuji" I just debuted,
なんと今日の24時から楽曲配信開始となります！いぇい！
it will be available for streaming starting tonight at midnight! Yay!
作編曲はマイソングのホリエショウタさん、そして
The composer and arranger is Horie Shota-san of My Song, and...
作詞は角巻わため……わため、私ですね（笑）
the lyrics are by Tsunomaki Watame... That's me, haha.
きみの花びきに続き、わためが書いてみました！
Following 'Kimi no Hanamizuki', I wrote this one myself!
今に至るまでの気持ちとかを、書かせていただいて、
Putting all my feelings up until now into it,
で、わためいとのみんなと、まだまだ先に進んで行くんだという気持ちをね、込めた、そんな楽曲となっております。
and with the feeling of pushing forward even further with everyone in Watamates, it's a song like that.
みんな、テンション上げたい時とか、
Everyone, when you want to raise your tension,
あとは、いつ作るか分かんないんだけど、またライブとかね、やる前とか、
and also, I'm not sure when it'll be made, but maybe before a live or something?
いや、やっぱデリデイだな。毎日聴いてほしいなと、思います！
Yeah, I think it's everyday! I'd be happy if you listened to it every day!
楽曲のリンクは概要欄にあの記載いたしますので、本日の24時、24時となります。
The link to the song will be in the description, and it releases today at 24:00, 24:00!
ぜひ、ぜひ、あの楽曲購入よろしくお願いいたします。
Please, please purchase the song!
そしてそして、夢見る羊の、ムービーが
And, and, the music video for "Yumemiru Hitsuji"
このあと！公開されまーす！やったー！
will be released right after this, yay!
いやもうね、振り付けがね、さっきもね、見てもらったと思うんだけど、もうめちゃくちゃ可愛くてね、素敵なんだよね。いつまでもお世話になってます。
Yeah, you saw the choreography earlier, right? It's super-duper cute and wonderful, and I'm always indebted to Hiromi-sensei,
あのHiromi先生に振り付けをしていただきまして、ね、頑張って、あの踊って、見たりしたので、ぜひ、ムービーの方もみんな
who choreographed it and also helped me dance and everything, so please everyone watch the MV too!
見て、くれ！お願いします！
Please watch it, please!
わあ！
Waaah!
いやあ…いやあ…。
Yeah... yeah...
終わりたくないの。まだ終わんないけどな。まだ終わんないけど、終わりたくないな。
I don't want it to end. I haven't finished yet, but I don't want it to end.
終わりたくない。なんか、あまりたくないな。
I don't want it to end, like, I really don't want it to end.
あ、なんか、あ、ブレイクダンス始まった！
Oh, wait, a breakdance started!
あ、やばい、ブレイクダンス始まった！あ、う、あ、ちょっと、私ブレイクダンスなんてやったことないから無理だったわ。
Oh, wait, breakdance started!
今日は、わための誕生日に最後まで付き合ってくれて、本当にありがとうございます！
Today, thank you so much for staying with me until the very end on Watame's birthday!
まだ終わんないけどね。
It's not over yet, though!
そしていつも支えて、くれている、え、スタジオの、Starry Cubeとか！
And thank you so much, as always, to the studio, Starry Cube, and others who always support me!
とか、え、Ue-sanとか！とか、あとわためたの、みんな！
And everyone...
とか、わためいとじゃなくても、ホロライブを応援してくれてる
And everyone, not just Watamates, but everyone who supports Hololive,
みんながいるからこの3歳の誕生日を迎えられたと思って、います！本当に、本当に、ありがとうございますいつも！
because everyone is here, I feel able to celebrate my 3rd birthday, so really, really, thank you so much, as always.
感謝しても、足りないぐらいです。
Even if I express my gratitude, it's not enough.
まだまだ、これから先も、7歳、8歳、え、9歳、10歳、11歳、100歳！
Still, from now on, 7 years old, 8 years old, 9 years old, 10 years old, 11 years old, 100 years old!
もうどんどんね、活動頑張っていきたいと思っているので、みんなの応援よろしくお願いします！
I want to keep working hard on my activities, so I'd appreciate everyone's continued support!
ということで、
So,
まだね、これじゃあ、もの足りないよね？
this still isn't enough, right?
まだここで、ね、終わるなんて思ってるやついねえよな？帰ってるやついねえよな？点取りますよ。お！
There's no one who thinks it's ending here, right? No one who's going home, right? I'll take the roll call, okay? Oh!
点取りますよ。
I'll take the roll call!
わためいと1番さん！
Watamates number 1-san,
わためいと2番さん、3番さん！初めて番号で呼んだわ。ごめんごめん、アドリブすみません。
Watamate number 2-san, 3-san, I called by number for the first time. Sorry, sorry, ad lib, sorry.
じゃあね、このあと、まあわためのライブといえば、アンコールだよねえ。
So, you know, Watame's live show means... encore, right?
ねえ！今日の来てくれたゲストさんたちもみんな待っててくれてんじゃ、ないのかな？このあとのアンコール見ないとみんな損しますのでね、
Nee, everyone who came as guests today have been waiting for us, right? If you don't watch the encore, everyone will lose out, so
ぜひ最後まで楽しんでって、ください！
please enjoy it until the very end!
では、ステージ、移動だー！
Well then, stage change!
あはい！あはい！あい！
Ahai! Ahai! Ai!
chu chu yeah! please me! chu chu yeah! without you!
Chu-chu-yeah! Please me! Chu-chu-yeah! Without you!
あー!なんてことだ 些細な過ちだ 自分のことに関わってタラッタラッタ手焼く
Ah, what a thing! A small blunder. Making mistakes with my own business.
どうして突然?逃げ切ったっていいでしょ? だけどなんだか気まぐれモードになり
How come suddenly? Saying I ran away is fine, right? But somehow, I get into a fickle mood,
そんな気分になっちゃって 始まりはそんな風で つまりはらしくないようで
and end up in that kind of mood. The beginning is like that, and the end doesn't seem like it.
でも今じゃ扉開けてほら 声が聴こえるよ さあ!行こう!どこででも
But now, open the door and look, a voice can be heard. Now! Let's go! Anywhere!
僕は君の翼になれる勇気があるよ! (please stay with me) どんな試練も怖くないその魔法があるから
I have the courage to become your wings! (Please stay with me) Because that magic exists where no trial is frightening.
(なんてってコングラチュレーション!) 初めて出会う世界に花束を贈ろう
(Congratulation!) Let's present a bouquet to a newly met world.
chu chu yeah ！ please me ！
Chu chu yeah! Please me!
chu chu yeah ！ without you
Chu chu yeah! Without you
あー ！ なんて こと だ 些細な 過ち
Ah, what a trivial mistake
自分の ことに タラ ラッタ ラッタ 手焼く
Fumbling all over myself
どうして 突然 ？ 逃げ切ったって いい でしょ ？
Why all of a sudden? Is it okay to run away?
だけど なんか 気まぐれ モード に なり
But somehow I get into a moody mode
そんな 気分 に なっちゃって
And end up feeling that way
始まり は そんな 風 で
It started out just like that
つまり は らしく ない よう で
Meaning it doesn't seem like me
でも 今 じゃ 扉 開けて
But now, open the door
ほら 声 が 聴こえる よ さあ ！ 行こう ！
Look, I can hear a voice. Now, let's go!
どこまで も 僕は 君の 翼に なれる 勇気が ある よ ！
No matter where, I have the courage to be your wings!
( please stay with me )
(Please stay with me)
どんな 試練 も 恐れ ない その 魔法 が ある から
Because I have that magic that fears no trials
( なんてったって コングラッチュ レーション ！ )
(No matter what, congratulations!)
初めて 出会う 世界 に 花束 を 贈ろう
Let's give a bouquet to this world we meet for the first time
( made in society )
(Made in society)
ただ この 瞬間 結ばれ る よ
We are bound together in this very moment
ちぐはぐな コミュニケーション ？
A disjointed communication?
でも 別に 構わ ない
But it doesn't really matter
明日 から 平和 なら ！
As long as tomorrow is peaceful!
chu chu yeah ！
Chu chu yeah!
without you ！
Without you!
あー ！ どうして また 素直に なれなくて
Ah, why can't I be honest again?
自分の ことで チュルチュルチュルチュル 火 吹く
Blowing up over my own self
ギア は そのまま スピード 上げ て いこ う
Let's keep the gear as is and boost the speed
だけど なんか 夕暮れ モード に なり
But somehow I get into a twilight mode
いつか を 思い出し ちゃっ て
And end up remembering some time in the past
一人 でいても 嫌 じゃ ない 誰 に 頼ら なく て も いい
It's not bad being alone, I don't need to rely on anyone
でも 扉の 向こう 騒がしい 声 が 聞き たい よ
But beyond the door, I want to hear noisy voices
今 ！ 行こう ！
Now! Let's go!
どこまで も 僕は 君 を 背中 に 乗せて 空 を 舞う よ ！
No matter where, I'll carry you on my back and dance through the sky!
( please fly with me )
(Please fly with me)
いつか 心 が 離れ て も その 時 は 笑っ て て
Even if our hearts drift apart someday, smile at that time
( なんてったって コングラッチュ レーション )
(No matter what, congratulations)
守り たい この 世界 に 青空 の ラプソディ
A rhapsody of the blue sky in this world I want to protect
( make me rhapsodic ！ )
(Make me rhapsodic!)
ただ いつまでも 奏で て い て よ
Just keep playing it forever
凸凹 な コンビネーション ？
A bumpy combination?
でも 別に 大丈夫 さ
But it's totally fine
明日 は また 平和 だ ！
Tomorrow will be peaceful again!
ほんの 小さな 傷 を 太陽 に さらし て 分け合っ た よ
Exposing tiny wounds to the sun, we shared them
君 と 痛み は 熱 さ の 中 に 融け て ゆく ！
Your pain melts away into the heat!
chu chu yeah ！ 粋な ビート 弾く 僕ら ！
Chu chu yeah! We play a stylish beat!
please me ！ 手 を 叩い て
Please me! Clapping our hands
chu chu yeah ！ ぶぎー な リズム で はしゃぐ 二人 ！
Chu chu yeah! Two people frolicking in a boogie rhythm!
without you ！ 飛び跳ね て さ
Without you! Jumping around
chu chu yeah ！ 粋な ビート 弾く 僕ら ！
Chu chu yeah! We play a stylish beat!
please me ！ 手 を 叩い て
Please me! Clapping our hands
chu chu yeah ！ ぶぎー な リズム で はしゃぐ アリーナ ！
Chu chu yeah! An arena frolicking in a boogie rhythm!
どこまで も ！
To the ends of the earth!
僕は 君の 翼に なれる 勇気が ある よ ！
I have the courage to be your wings!
( please stay with me )
(Please stay with me)
どんな 試練 も 恐れ ない その 魔法 が ある から
Because I have that magic that fears no trials
( なんてったって コングラッチュ レーション )
(No matter what, congratulations)
君 と 出会い 世界 は 花束 に 溢れ た
Meeting you, the world overflowed with bouquets
( made in society )
(Made in society)
ただ その 瞬間 結ばれ た よ
We were bound together in that exact moment
ちぐはぐな コミュニケーション ？
A disjointed communication?
でも 別に 構わ ない
But it doesn't really matter
明日 が 平和 なら
As long as tomorrow is peaceful
chu chu yeah ！ please me ！
Chu chu yeah! Please me!
息 を 切ら し て
Catching our breath
without you ！
Without you!
角巻わため 超絶誕生日記念グッズ このあと21時から販売開始！
Tsunomaki Watame's Super Birthday Festival goods on sale starting at 21:00!
ラバーマット、わためとマフラー、わためいとスリッパの3種類です。
Rubber mat, Watame & muffler, and Watame & slippers — 3 items in total.
そしてフルセットを購入すると、直筆サイン付きポストカードと特典ボイスがついてきます！
Purchasing the full set includes a signed postcard and bonus voice!
数量限定ではなくすべてにサインとメッセージを書きますので、ぜひお買い求めください。
It's not limited; I'll sign and write messages on all of them, so please buy!
そしてそして！角巻わため新オリジナル曲「夢見る羊」マイソングを手掛けた堀江晶太さんに曲を作り下していただき、わためが作詞をしました！
And what's more! My new original song "Yumemiru Hitsuji" composed by Shota Horie, with lyrics by me!
このあと24時から各種音楽配信サービスにて配信開始！
Streaming starts at 24:00 on various music distribution services!
叶えたい未来へ 心の準備OK？
Ready in heart for the future we want to fulfill?
さあ、一歩踏み出して いっせーの、せっ！
Now, take a step forward. On three, go!
このあとすぐ21時30分、9時半からはメンバーシップ限定でライブのアフターパーティをしますよ！
Right after this at 21:30, we'll have a membership-exclusive live afterparty!
夢見る羊を聞きながら待機しててくださいね！
Please wait while listening to "Yumemiru Hitsuji"!
あ、今夜の
Ah, tonight's...
夢見る羊のムービーに メンバーシップ限定配信に
dream-seeing sheep's movie and members-only stream,
レッツゴー！
let's go!